<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DIY on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</title>
    <link>/tags/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DIY on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homelab</title>
      <link>/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homelab/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you just get tired of paying AWS &amp;amp; Digital Ocean. A quick sketch of my homelab, inspired by the good folks at r/homelab.
The main goal of the project was to enable the quick creation of Virtual Machines (or containers), accessible by subdomain such as project1.mydomain.net, project2.mydomain.net, etc., all under a single dynamic IP address. I managed to make it work pretty well, with a little help from NGINX for reverse proxying, pfsense for local DNS and routing, ddclient for dynamic DNS, Proxmox for hypervisor management, and freeNAS for shared storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing &amp; Modeling, Online Tools</title>
      <link>/3d_printing_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3d_printing_notes/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been teaching an evening class at the Oregon State University Craft Center in “3D modeling and printing.” I don’t know a ton about this topic, to be honest. But I know a little more than I did a year ago, and it was hard-earned knowledge. Why not share it?
At OSU it seems like I can’t walk out the door without bumping into a 3d printer (and students and faculty get access to them), but I found very little in-person information about how to do basic 3d design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gainclone Amplifier</title>
      <link>/gainclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gainclone/</guid>
      <description>This one was a long time in the making. The case is cherry, the face plate and knobs are copper. The left knob is input select, center volume, and the right knob is a rotary dimmer switch for the (incandescent) backlight on the volume knob. Sounds absolutely beautiful, looks just as good, with more coats of polyurethane than I kept track of! Thanks to all of the people at diyaudio.com, especially BrianGT, who made the PCB boards I used, and to my then landlord Steve who let me use his shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headphone Amp</title>
      <link>/headamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/headamp/</guid>
      <description>The second iteration of the headphone amp was the same internal design, packed into a slightly smaller, sleeker container. This one has a much more solid feel to it. It&amp;rsquo;s based on Chu Moy&amp;rsquo;s design; I checked the first iteration using a scope and it checks out nice, no clipping and the input/output resistances are good (100k in, theoretical 0 out.)
       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
