<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infrastructure on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</title>
    <link>/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infrastructure on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DataScience@OSU</title>
      <link>/ds-at-osu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ds-at-osu/</guid>
      <description>DS@OSU was a project I had the priveledge of co-leading (along with Dr. Robin Pappas) in collaboration with Oregon State UIT. Driven by a broadly recognized need to enable accessible and scalable infrastructure for data science (and related) instruction, we embarked on campus-wide needs assessments, a steering committee, technical and faculty advisory committees, fact-finding sessions with peer institutions, and eventually platform implemention.
Based on the Zero to JupyterHub kubernetes-based deployment pattern, DS@OSU provides a number of additional custom features:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab</title>
      <link>/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homelab/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you just get tired of paying AWS &amp;amp; Digital Ocean. A quick sketch of my homelab, inspired by the good folks at r/homelab.
The main goal of the project was to enable the quick creation of Virtual Machines (or containers), accessible by subdomain such as project1.mydomain.net, project2.mydomain.net, etc., all under a single dynamic IP address. I managed to make it work pretty well, with a little help from NGINX for reverse proxying, pfsense for local DNS and routing, ddclient for dynamic DNS, Proxmox for hypervisor management, and freeNAS for shared storage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
