<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</title>
    <link>/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Shawn T. O&#39;Neil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding Long-COVID: Temporal Topic Modeling EHR Data</title>
      <link>/topic_modeling_pasc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic_modeling_pasc/</guid>
      <description>In this study, currently available as a preprint awaiting peer-review, I apply an unsupervised learning technique known as Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) to identify condition clusters across millions of patients in the N3C database. Such clusters are not guaranteed to be related to COVID-19, however. To identify those that are, we look at how patients are assigned to clusters before and after COVID-19 infection, integrating the probabilistic nature of LDA and supervised models (repeated-measures logistic regression) to predict how patients will migrate toward or away from a cluster post-infection, moderated by demographic factors such as age, sex, and wave of infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Analysis of Nerf Blasters and Darts</title>
      <link>/nerf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nerf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Shawn O&amp;rsquo;Neil and Katie Drueen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE60317 Online Algorithms For Computational Finance</title>
      <link>/online-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/online-finance/</guid>
      <description>This class was very interesting; we studied some of the basics of online algorithms as well as some applications to computational finance. Perhaps the most intriguing parts (for someone already familiar with online algorithms) were what we learned about classic computational finance, such as Black-Scholes-Merton.
This &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo; is a review of the main result of an interesting paper, entitled &amp;ldquo;Making Decisions in the Face of Uncertainty: How to Pick a Winner Almost Every Time,&amp;rdquo; by Awerbuch et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE60647 Data Mining, Predicting on Slashdot</title>
      <link>/slashdot-predicting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slashdot-predicting/</guid>
      <description>Much of the research I performed during my Master&amp;rsquo;s was on the newsvendor problem, which deals with attempting to guess the demand for short-lived products so as to maximize profits. Unfortunately, data about newspaper sales is tough to come by. So, why not use an online equivalent? This project aims at predicting the number of comments a Slashdot story will generate given text which appears in the summary.
However, since we are interested in looking at the number of comments as a demand for a product to be sold, we don&amp;rsquo;t stop there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCSE60171 Artificial Intelligence, Learning to Play Games</title>
      <link>/learning-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning-ai/</guid>
      <description>I did this project with Allison Regier. It&amp;rsquo;s not too difficult to write a program which uses an exhaustive search to play a game. What this requires, though, is some way to evaluate one board against another to tell which moves to make. Usually such a comparison function is hand written.
We asked whether it was possible to write a generic board evaluation function which would learn a preference over board states by playing many games, either against itself or a hand coded evaluation function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
